Guide to the Vassar College Dean of the Faculty Records, 1901-2009
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Dean of the Faculty Records
1901-2009
Vassar College Dean of the Faculty
42.8 cubic feet (46 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The records contain material related to the operations of the Dean of the Faculty office, including events planning, faculty management, buildings operations, reports, and personnel files.
Administrative History
The office of the Dean of the Faculty was established in 1962, with Marion Tait becoming the first Dean of the Faculty. This office not only assisted the President directly with matters pertaining to educational policies, curriculum, dealing with office and classroom assignments, and the budget for educational equipment, but also dealt with educational policy issues in the absence of the President. While the position of the Dean of the Faculty was replaced by that of the Dean of the College in 1981, it was reestablished in 1991 and "continues to serve as 'chief academic officer', providing 'intellectual leadership... for all academic departments' and working jointly with the President to develop educational policies."* The assistant to the Dean of the Faculty currently handles event planning.
*Patkus, Ronald D., and Elizabeth A. Daniels. An Administrative History of Vassar College: 1861-2003. Poughkeepsie, NY: Vassar College, 2004.
Chronology
1913 The position of Dean of the College was established at Vassar College. Ella McCaleb served as the first Dean.
1962 Dean of the College position was divided into the Dean of the Faculty and Dean of Studies. Marion Tait became first Dean of the Faculty.
1978 H. Patrick Sullivan is appointed Dean of the Faculty.
1981 Jan Office of the Dean of the Faculty was officially renamed to Dean of the College.
1988 Nancy Dye replaces H. Patrick Sullivan as Dean of the College.
1990 Sep Office of the Dean of the College was renamed back to Dean of the Faculty.
1994 A new Office of the Dean of the College was created from the Office of the Dean of Student Life and responsibilities previously overseen by the Dean of the Faculty, including oversight of the Office of the Dean of Studies. Colton Johnson, formerly Acting Dean of Student Life, was appointed Dean of the College.
Scope and Content Note
The records contain material related to the operations of the Dean of the Faculty office, including events planning, faculty management, buildings operations, reports, and personnel files.
Access
Personnel files and other select files are closed to research. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Dean of the College, Dean of the Faculty Records
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Buildings
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Administrative Offices and Functions
Encoding Information
Encoded by Madeleine Amodio, June 2011. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, February 2024.
Acquisition Information
Series I was transferred in 2010 (A2010-017), Series II was transferred in 2007 (A2007-050), Series III was transferred in 2014 (A2014-015), and Series IV was transferred in 2002 (A2002-009).
Series List
- Series I. Records of the Assistant to the Dean of the Faculty, 1975-2009; (9 boxes)
  This series is arranged in order of acquisition.
- Series II. Reports and Personnel Files, 1968-2000; (8 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by title.
- Series III. Faculty Personnel Files [RESTRICTED], 2001-2003; (24 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by last name.
- Series IV. Faculty Load Records, 1901-1970; (5 boxes)
  This series is arranged chronologically, with miscellaneous materials filed at the end of the sequence.
Container List
- SERIES I. Records of the Assistant to the Dean of the Faculty, 1975-2009
  - Events
    - Faculty Forums, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Faculty/Staff Lists, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - German Drill Instructors, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Hughs Scholars Program, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies questionnaire responses (favorable), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Jewish Studies questionnaire responses (unfavorable), 1984 (Box 1)
    - Lodging, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
    - New Faculty Orientation, 1998 Aug 26 (Box 1)
    - Office Renovations (Box 1)
    - Opening Days, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Penrose, Roger (dinner), 1993 Mar 4 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Publications, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Reference Copies of Previous Faculty Publications, 1979-1983 (Box 1)
    - Reference Copies of Previous Faculty Publications, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1980-1984 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1984-1990 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Religion, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Academic Buildings, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Athletics, 1997 Sep 9 (Box 1)
    - Avery Hall, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Avery Hall, 1994; (2 folders) (Box 1)
    - Avery Hall Move, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Blodgett Hall Project, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Departmental Review, 1992 (Box 1)
    - DOF Budget Numbers, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
    - Dye, Nancy, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Expenses for Self-Study, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Curriculum Retreat, 1990 Feb 3 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Forum, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
    - Faculty Memos, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Field Work Move, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Financial Aid, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Greenberg, Douglas, 1994 Feb 24 (Box 2)
    - Guy, Rosa (lecture), 1993 Mar 30 (Box 2)
    - Hughs Minority Scholars, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Institutional Research, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Irving, John (Krieger lecture), 1993 Apr 19 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1992 Sep 4 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1993 Sep 3 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1994 Sep 10 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1995 Sep 8 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1996 Sep 23 (Box 2)
    - Jazz Festival, 1997 Sep 20 (Box 2)
    - Mornings with Marla, 1989 (Box 2)
    - NEH Summer Institute, 1997 (Box 2)
    - New England basement work, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Fainstein, Norman (DoF), 1995-1996 (Box 2)
    - O'Rourke, P.J. (Krieger lecture), 1995 Feb 28 (Box 2)
    - Piercey, Jan (dinner), 1995 Oct 5 (Box 2)
    - United Way, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Wassenstein, Wendy (Krieger lecture), 1996 Apr 9 (Box 2)
    - Akcay, Cavet lecture, 2003 Apr 23 (Box 2)
    - Beyer, Frank, 2002 Oct 27 (Box 2)
    - Book Party, 2003 May 6 (Box 2)
    - Chen, Da, 2002 Sep 23 (Box 2)
    - Coalition Dinner, 2002 Sep 26 (Box 2)
    - Commencement, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Delmas Visiting Professor, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Entertainment, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
    - Evening of Musical Performance, 1999 Dec 9 (Box 2)
    - Ford Scholars, 2004 Sep 13 (Box 2)
    - Ford Scholars Symposium, 2002 Feb 13 (Box 2)
    - Gardner, Howard, 2001 Apr 24 (Box 2)
    - Hardho, Joy (writer-in-residence), 2002 Feb 20 (Box 2)
    - Heaney, Seamus (Elizabeth Bishop lecture and Novy lecture), 2000 Oct 3 (Box 2)
    - Intellectual Buffet (Box 2)
    - Irwin, Robert W., 1999 Apr 26 (Box 2)
    - Jian, Chen (lecture and dinner), 2002 Nov 7 (Box 2)
    - McGann, Jerome, 2003 Apr 10 (Box 2)
    - Olds, Sharon (Eliz. Bishop poet), 2001 Nov 27 (Box 2)
    - Oliviera, Carmen, 2002 Oct 22 (Box 2)
    - Pinsky, Robert, 1999 Feb 16 (Box 3)
    - Rhodes, Richard (Freshman Course lecture), 2001 Sep 20 (Box 3)
    - Rogers, Pat, 2002 Nov 19 (Box 3)
    - Simic, Charles (Eliz. Bishop lecture), 2002 Oct 3 (Box 3)
    - Sletkin, Yuri, 2003 Nov 13 (Box 3)
    - Slotkin, Richard, 2002 Oct 24 (Box 3)
    - Spiegelman, Art, 2002 Oct 28 (Box 3)
    - Sudan Studies Symposium, 2002 Nov 7-9 (Box 3)
    - Tharp, Twyla (Box 3)
    - URSI Symposium, 2004 Sep 29 (Box 3)
    - Vahdat, Farzin, 2002 Sep 30 (Box 3)
    - Sitomer Lectures
      - Botstein, Leon (Sitomer lecture), 1988 Apr 19 (Box 3)
      - Broner, Esther (Sitomer lecture), 1989 Apr 5 (Box 3)
      - Paley, Michael (Sitomer lecture), 1990 Apr 19 (Box 3)
      - Ozick, Cynthia (Sitomer lecture), 1991 May 6 (Box 3)
      - Broshi, Magan (Sitomer lecture), 1992 Mar 30 (Box 3)
      - Dimant, Dvora (Sitomer lecture), 1994 Apr 12 (Box 3)
      - Avineri, Shlomo (Sitomer lecture), 1994 Nov 10 (Box 3)
      - Monk, Daniel Bertrand (Sitomer lecture), 1997 Apr 16 (Box 3)
      - Kaplan, Alice (Sitomer lecture), 1998 Apr 21 (Box 3)
      - Anissimov, Myriam (Sitomer lecture), 1999 Apr 20 (Box 3)
      - Brown, Phil (Sitomer lecture), 2000 Apr 25 (Box 3)
      - Weber, Donald (Sitomer lecture), 2001 Apr 17 (Box 3)
      - Hyman, Paula (Sitomer lecture), 2002 Apr 22 (Box 3)
      - Englander, Nathan (Sitomer lecture), 2003 Apr 1 (Box 3)
      - Judt, Tony (Sitomer lecture), 2005 Feb 22 (Box 3)
    - Academic Buildings Service Requests, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    - Boxing Symposium, 1996 Mar 29 (Box 3)
    - Cleaver, Kathleen (dinner), 2001 Feb 27 (Box 3)
    - Hartman, Heidi, 1998 Apr 13 (Box 3)
    - Hofmeister, Timothy Dinner, 1996 May 13 (Box 3)
    - Indian Dance Troupe, 1994 Sep 20 (Box 3)
    - Mamiya, Larry Reception, 1996 Oct 30 (Box 3)
    - Maza, Sarah (Matthew Vassar lecture), 2001 Apr 19 (Box 3)
    - Murray, Albert Dinner, 45038 (Box 3)
    - Okihiro, Gary (Ethnic Studies) lecture and dinner, 2001 Nov 15 (Box 3)
    - Said, Edward (Matthew Vassar lecturer) Dinner, 1995 Nov 29 (Box 3)
    - Sayles, John (Luce lecturer) Dinner, 1991 Apr 18 (Box 3)
    - Schneider, Elizabeth (lecture and dinner), 2000 Nov 8 (Box 3)
    - Short, Bobby, 1998 Oct 3 (Box 3)
    - Time Machine mini-symposium, 2001 Mar 28 (Box 3)
    - Tsao, Thomas (lecture and dinner), 2001 Jan 31 (Box 3)
    - Walvin, James (dinner), 1999 Sep 13 (Box 3)
    - Wollen, Peter Dinner, 1990 Oct 3 (Box 3)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol (Freshman lecture and dinner), 1998 Sep 14 (Box 3)
    - Theroux, Paul (Freshman lecture and dinner), 1996 Sep 30 (Box 3)
    - Wolff, Tobias (Freshman lecture and dinner), 1997 Sep 11 (Box 3)
    - McBride, James (Freshman lecture and dinner), 1999 Sep 16 (Box 3)
    - Alterman, Jon, 2004 Apr 20 (Box 4)
    - Appachana, Anjana, 2003 Sep 18 (Box 4)
    - Athletics Party (Box 4)
    - Bagbey and Beowulf, 2004 Feb 18 (Box 4)
    - Balaban, John, 2004 Feb 24 (Box 4)
    - Beattie, Ann, 1997 Fall (Box 4)
    - Benhabib, Seyla, 2004 Apr 6 (Box 4)
    - Bill T, 2004 May 2 (Box 4)
    - Bill T (Dinner), 2004 May 2 (Box 4)
    - Billington, James, 2003 Oct 27 (Box 4)
    - Brown, Sally (Lehman lecture), 2006 Apr 8 (Box 4)
    - Browning, Christopher, 2005 Feb 9 (Box 4)
    - Byram, Michael, 2003 Nov 17 (Box 4)
    - Campo, Rafael, 2004 Sep 12 (Box 4)
    - Cliffe, Michelle, 2002 Feb 4 (Box 4)
    - Cocktail Party, May 20 (Box 4)
    - Cocktail Party, 2004 Sep 10 (Box 4)
    - Cocktail Party, 2005 Feb 4 (Box 4)
    - Collins, Billy, 2004 Mar 25 (Box 4)
    - Davies, Carol, 2001 Feb 28 (Box 4)
    - Davis, Angela, 1995 Fall (Box 4)
    - Davis, Devra, 2003 Feb 26-27 (Box 4)
    - Diller, Liz, 2001 Apr 5 (Box 4)
    - Economic Development Conference, 1997 (Box 4)
    - Ekland-Olson, Sheldon, 2004 Oct 7-8 (Box 4)
    - Faculty Retreat, 2005 May 9 (Box 4)
    - Finkelman, Paul, 2004 Jan 29 (Box 4)
    - Foresta, Don (lecture and dinner), 2005 Mar 2 (Box 4)
    - Gilb, Dagoberto, Feb 15 (Box 4)
    - Gould, F., ENVS lecture, 2002 Apr 24 (Box 4)
    - Guillermopreito, Alma, 2004 Nov 16 (Box 4)
    - Habermas lecture (Box 4)
    - Holocaust Panel, 2004 Nov 18 (Box 4)
    - Hyde, Lewis, 2004 Mar 29 (Box 4)
    - Intellectual Buffet, 2004 May 13 (Box 4)
    - Kinsella, John, 2004 Apr 25 (Box 4)
    - Kluger, Ruth, 2005 Apr 21 (Box 4)
    - Kouminykaa, Yusef, 2004 Nov 4 (Box 4)
    - Lahiri, Jhumpa, 2004 Feb 12 (Box 4)
    - Learning Spaces Conference, 2004 Oct 22-24 (Box 4)
    - Lee, Spike, and Budd Schulberg, 2001 Nov 28 (Box 4)
    - Lynn, David, 2003 Dec 2 (Box 4)
    - Marcus, Jane (lecture and dinner), 2001 Mar 1 (Box 4)
    - Miron, Dan, 2004 Apr 29 (Box 4)
    - NCBI Workshop, 2003 Mar 25-26 (Box 4)
    - NEH: Hohn and von der Emde, 2005 May 21 (Box 4)
    - Orgell, Stephen, 2004 Sep 23 (Box 4)
    - Page, Barbara - Party, 2003 May 7 (Box 4)
    - Preston, Richard, 1995 Oct 2 (Box 4)
    - Rio Raigadas, David, 2003 Sep 29 (Box 4)
    - Romer, Paul (Crego lecture), 2001 Apr 26 (Box 4)
    - Schoeps, Julius, 2005 Apr 12 (Box 4)
    - Sharp Dinner Party, 2004 Nov 19 (Box 4)
    - Shore, Jane (lecture and dinner), 2000 Feb 21 (Box 4)
    - Steel, Claude, 2004 Sep 22 (Box 4)
    - Stone, Robert, 2004 Sep 30 (Box 4)
    - Task force for Sept. 11, 2001 (Box 4)
    - Teaching with Technology Forum, 2004 Apr 7 (Box 4)
    - Thiebaud, Wayne (Box 4)
    - URSI 2003-2004, 2003 Sep 24 (Box 4)
    - Videoconferencing, 2005 May 16 (Box 4)
    - Wilkes, Michael, 2004 Apr 21 (Box 4)
    - Williams, Terry Tempest, 1994 Sep 27 (Box 4)
    - Wise, Tim (lecture and dinner), 2005 Mar 1 (Box 4)
    - Zagejewski, Adam, 2004 Apr 20 (Box 4)
    - Paige Ackerson-Killy Din, 2008 Oct 7 (Box 5)
    - Africana Studies 40th Anniversary Dinner, N. Rooks speaker, 2009 Apr 17 (Box 5)
    - An Evening of Black Voices, 2005 Dec 8 (Box 5)
    - Armitage, Simon, 2007 Oct 10 (Box 5)
    - KB-- Assignments and Projects (Box 5)
    - Bergon, Frank, 2006 Feb 24 (Box 5)
    - Bharucha, Jamshed- Grant Fund lecture and Dinner- 5:30, 2008 Feb 21 (Box 5)
    - Bibliography Reception, 2006 May 10 (Box 5)
    - Bikel, Theodore, 2007 Feb 10-18 (Box 5)
    - Bratman, Michael, 2005 Nov 3-4 (Box 5)
    - Kathy Brown Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Chairs Meeting, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    - Chairs Meeting, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Chairs Meeting, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - Jeff Chang lecture and Dinner, 2008 March 24-27 (Box 5)
    - Cocktail Party, 2008 Sep 18 (Box 5)
    - Cocktail Party, 2005 Sep 23 (Box 5)
    - Cocktail Party, 2009 Sep 10 (Box 5)
    - Consortium for Faculty Diversity, 2006 Nov 3-5 (Box 5)
    - Crenshaw, 2006 May 4 (Box 5)
    - CSMP Conference, 2006 Nov (Box 5)
    - CSMP Conference, 2006 Nov 3-5 (Box 5)
    - D, Chuck, 2007 Nov 6 (Box 5)
    - Davies, Adam, 2006 Oct 3 (Box 5)
    - Davis, Lydia, 2008 Feb 6 (Box 5)
    - Dean's Cocktail Party, 2007 Sept 20 (Box 5)
    - Dean's House - Sharp (Box 5)
    - Nancy Dye Party, 1994 May 5 (Box 5)
    - Diversity Panel, 2006 Sept 14 (Box 5)
    - Donnelly, Liza, 2005 Nov 10 (Box 5)
    - Duster, Troy, 2008 March 4 (Box 5)
    - Empire Games, 2009 Summer (Box 5)
    - End of Year Party, 1998 (Box 5)
    - English Dept, 2007 Aug 31 (Box 5)
    - Entertainment- Various (Box 5)
    - von Eschen, Penny, 2007 Nov 7 (Box 5)
    - Ethnic Studies, 2007 March 31 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Diversity Retreat, 2008 May 9 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Lists, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Lists, 2007-2008 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Retreat, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Retreat, 2004 May 20 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Retreat, 2009 May 11 (Box 5)
    - Featherstone, Lisa, 2005 Sept 19 (Box 5)
    - Frances Fergusson Party, 2005 May 25 (Box 5)
    - Ford Scholars, 1996-1998; (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - George Saunders Gifford lecture, 2008 Oct 29 (Box 5)
    - Gladman, Renee, 2008 March 27 (Box 5)
    - Glissant, Eduoard, 2007 March 26 (Box 5)
    - Ground Water Conference, 2005 Oct 29 (Box 5)
    - Halloween Part, 2004 Oct 29 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Handbook Governance, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Handbooks, Governance, 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - Judy Hanna Party, 2005 Dec 12 (Box 5)
    - Hoehn, Maria (Box 5)
    - Horowitz, Murray (Box 5)
    - Harrison, Jeffery, 2006 Nov 14 (Box 6)
    - How To Get Published, 2007 Apr 10 (Box 6)
    - Howard, Richard, 2005 Oct 29 (Box 6)
    - Chunglian Al Huang, 2006 May 1 (Box 6)
    - Intellectual Buffet, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Issues and Answers for Wednesday's Staff Meeting w/NSD and JH and CS and KB (Box 6)
    - Johnson, Glen (lecture and dinner), 2005 Sep 13 (Box 6)
    - Kastan, David, 2005 Dec (Box 6)
    - Keothe, John Reading and Dinner, 2007 Apr 19 (Box 6)
    - Kluger, Ruth, 2008 Apr 3 (Box 6)
    - Kolbert, Elizabeth, 2008 Sep 25 (Box 6)
    - Kooser, Ted, 2006 Feb 20 (Box 6)
    - Kristeva, Julia, 2008 Oct 30 (Box 6)
    - Lee, Li-Young - Elizabeth Bishop lecture (Box 6)
    - Lefkowitz, Lori (Sitomer lecture), 2005 Mar 28 (Box 6)
    - Brad Leithausr and Mary Jo Salter Writers in Residence, 2006 Feb 16 (Box 6)
    - Lelyveld, Joe, 2005 Sep 12 (Box 6)
    - Luncheon Grounds Crew, 2007 Dec 7 (Box 6)
    - Barbara Buhler Lynes Novy (lecture and dinner), 2005 Nov 1 (Box 6)
    - Matsuda, Mari, 2005 Sep 21 (Box 6)
    - Rob Nixon Anne McClintock, 2008 Nov 5-6 (Box 6)
    - Mentoring Dinner, 2008 Sep 3 (Box 6)
    - Mentor/mentee dinner, 2007 Sep 19 (Box 6)
    - Mentors Mentees Dinner, 2009 Sep 16 (Box 6)
    - Thylias Moss Elizabeth Bishop Poet, 2009 Oct 1 (Box 6)
    - Paul Muldoon Eliz Bishop Poet, 2006 Sep 28 (Box 6)
    - Harryette Muller Elizabeth Bishop Poet, 2007 Sep 18 (Box 6)
    - Murray, Les lecture, 2007 Mar 6 (Box 6)
    - Mendelson, David (Sitomer lecture), 2008 Apr 15 (Box 6)
    - Music and Technology Conference, 2005 Jun 9-10 (Box 6)
    - Music Faculty Dinner, 2008 Oct 14 (Box 6)
    - Musicales (Box 6)
    - Native American Poetry Event J. McAdams, G. Henry, K. Blaeser, 2007 Nov 8 (Box 6)
    - New Faculty, 2000 (Box 6)
    - New Faculty dinner, 2001 Feb 13 (Box 6)
    - Depts/New Faculty Dinner, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
    - Patrice Nganang (lecture and dinner), 2006 Nov 6 (Box 6)
    - New Year -Orientation, Faculty Association, 2001 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2003-2004 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2004-2005 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2005-2006 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2006-2007 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2007-2008 (Box 6)
    - New Year, 2008-2009 (Box 6)
    - O'Brien, Tim, 2007 Sep 27 (Box 6)
    - Louise Erdich William Gifford lecture, 2006 Oct 10 (Box 6)
    - Old Observatory Project (Box 6)
    - Mary Oliver Eliz Bishop Poet, 2005 Oct 6 (Box 6)
    - Michael Ondaatje Gifford lecture, 2007 Oct 24 (Box 6)
    - ZZ Packer lecture and reading and dinner Writer-in-Residence, 2009 Feb 4 (Box 6)
    - Phillips, Jayne Anne, 2006 Oct 30 (Box 6)
    - PKAL/Facilities workshop, 2004 Oct 22-24 (Box 6)
    - Powers, Richard, 2005 Nov 16 (Box 6)
    - Purchase, Bruce, 2005 Sep (Box 6)
    - Raymond Ave Association (Box 6)
    - Reception - untenured faculty, 2009 May 4 (Box 6)
    - Salman Rushdie William Starr/Freshman Course, 2006 Sep 20 (Box 6)
    - Schamus, James, 2005 Oct 23 (Box 6)
    - Richard Schenchner lecture and Dinner, 2007 Feb 21 (Box 6)
    - Sudan Association (Box 6)
    - Sharp, Ron (Box 6)
    - Ailene Sitomer, (2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Summer Programs, 2004 (Box 7)
    - 3 Poets - Readings and Dinner, 2007 Mar 7-8 (Box 7)
    - James Taylor lecture reception, and dinner Adams pa, 2008 Apr 24 (Box 7)
    - Teaching with Technology Forum, 2007 Apr 25 (Box 7)
    - Technology Forum, 2005 Apr 13 (Box 7)
    - Teaching with Technology, 2008 Apr 21 (Box 7)
    - Tymoeko, Dmitri, 2009 Feb 24 (Box 7)
    - Trustee Luncheon, 2009 Oct 16 (Box 7)
    - Trustees and Faculty lunches (Box 7)
    - URSI and Psych, 1995 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 1996 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 1999 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 2001 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 2008 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 1997-1998 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 2005 Sep 28 (Box 7)
    - URSI 20 years, 2006 Sept 27 (Box 7)
    - URSI, 2007 Sep 26 (Box 7)
    - Vahdat, Farzin, 2006 Oct 31 (Box 7)
    - Vidgerman, Patsy, 2007 April 17 (Box 7)
    - Amina Wadud - lecture cancelled, 2007 Apr 10 (Box 7)
    - Walcott, Derek, 2006 April 11 (Box 7)
    - Colson Whitehead Writer in Residence lecture and Dinner, 2007 Feb 20 (Box 7)
    - Wright, Beverly, 2006 Feb 15 (Box 7)
    - Young, James, 2005 Sept 27 (Box 7)
    - Zinn, Howard, 2005 Sept 22 (Box 7)
    - Entertainment, 1989-2009; (17 folders) (Box 8)
  - Subseries II. Miscellaneous
    - Faculty Housing (Box 9)
    - Dean of Faculty House (Box 9)
    - Pratt House Renovation, 2006 (Box 9)
    - Pratt House, 2002 (Box 9)
    - Pratt House (Box 9)
    - Pratt House, 2005 (Box 9)
    - Pratt House - Re-decoration, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Pratt House Gifts and Art Works (Box 9)
    - Pratt House - Fees for Use (Box 9)
    - Pratt House Calendar Forms (Box 9)
    - Pratt House Reservations, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Pratt House - General (Box 9)
    - [Computing]-Management Information System RFP, 1983 (Box 9)
    - [Search Committees], 1984-1985 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee - Correspondence and Background Information, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1975-1976 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1977-1978 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1982-1983 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
    - Faculty Procedure Committee Materials, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Chronology of the College Charter (Box 9)
    - "Rules of the Faculty, 1865-1920,", undated (Box 9)
    - Information for New Faculty packet, 1988-1995; (7 folders) (Box 9)
    - Vassar College, "The Equity Scorecard,", 2005 Jun; (2 copies) [RESTRICTED] (Box 9)
    - Termination and leave lists, 1998-1999; [RESTRICTED] (Box 9)
- Series II. Reports and Personnel Files, 1968-2000
  - Annual Reports - Departments, circa 1975-1984 (Box 10)
  - Annual Reports - Dean of the Faculty / Dean of the College, circa 1974-1988 (Box 11)
  - Annual Reports - Dean of the College, circa 1986-1989 (Box 12)
  - Annual Reports - Dean of Studies, 1989-1990 (Box 12)
  - Annual Reports - Dean of Students, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
  - Budgets and Personnel Files, circa 1986-1993; [RESTRICTED] (Box 12)
  - Budgets and Personnel Files, circa 1993-2000; [RESTRICTED] (Box 13)
  - Comprehensive Planning Report, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Departmental Reviews and Self-Studies, A-C, circa 1987-1994 (Box 14)
  - Departmental Reviews and Self-Studies, D-H, circa 1987-1994 (Box 15)
  - Departmental Reviews and Self-Studies, H-P, circa 1987-1994 (Box 16)
  - Departmental Reviews and Self Studies, P-Z, circa 1987-1994 (Box 17)
- Series III. Faculty Personnel Files, 2001-2003; [RESTRICTED]
  - Ad-Bas, 2001-2003 (Box 18 (Box 1))
  - Bat-Bon, 2001-2003 (Box 19 (Box 2))
  - Bor-Can, 2001-2003 (Box 20 (Box 3))
  - Car-Cle, 2001-2003 (Box 21 (Box 4))
  - Cli-Cu, 2001-2003 (Box 22 (Box 5))
  - Da-Dunc, 2001-2003 (Box 23 (Box 6))
  - Dunn-Fe, 2001-2003 (Box 24 (Box 7))
  - Fi-Grah, 2001-2003 (Box 25 (Box 8))
  - Gray-Hi, 2001-2003 (Box 26 (Box 9))
  - Ho-Is, 2001-2003 (Box 27 (Box 10))
  - Ja-Kan, 2001-2003 (Box 28 (Box 11))
  - Kap-Kum, 2001-2003 (Box 29 (Box 12))
  - Kur-Lon, 2001-2003 (Box 30 (Box 13))
  - Lot-McAd, 2001-2003 (Box 31 (Box 14))
  - McAu-Mi, 2001-2003 (Box 32 (Box 15))
  - Mo-N, 2001-2003 (Box 33 (Box 16))
  - Of-Pl, 2001-2003 (Box 34 (Box 17))
  - Po-Re, 2001-2003 (Box 35 (Box 18))
  - Ro-Rus, 2001-2003 (Box 36 (Box 19))
  - Ruu-Sh, 2001-2003 (Box 37 (Box 20))
  - Si-Sw, 2001-2003 (Box 38 (Box 21))
  - Ta-Vil, 2001-2003 (Box 39 (Box 22))
  - Viv-Wil, 2001-2003 (Box 40 (Box 23))
  - Win-Zu, 2001-2003 (Box 41 (Box 24))
- Series IV. Faculty Load Records, 1901-1970
  - 1901-1920 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1921-1922 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1922-1923 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1923-1924 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1924-1925 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1925-1926 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1926-1927 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1927-1928 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1928-1929 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1929-1930 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1930-1931 (Box 42 (Box 1))
  - 1931-1932 (Box 43 (Box 2))
  - 1932-1933 (Box 43 (Box 2))